Adriana Paiva

+1 416-523-0873 | itsadrianapaiva@gmail.com | Toronto, ON, Canada <u>itsadrianapaiva.com | github.com/itsadrianapaiva</u> | <u>linkedin.com/in/itsadrianapaiva</u>

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Developer specialized in web applications, backed by **8 years** in project management and digital strategy within the **U.S.** marketing industry. Delivered marketing projects with **99%** client satisfaction and achieved **58%** annual ROI growth, demonstrating adaptability and client focus. Expertise in **Front-end** development using **TypeScript**, **React.js and Node.js.**

CORE COMPETENCIES

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: JavaScript | TypeScript | Python

FRAMEWORKS: React.js | Next.js | Express.js

BACK-END: Node.js | REST APIs

DATABASES & DATA: SQL | MySQL | MongoDB **DEVELOPER TOOLS**: Git | GitHub | Cloud Services

SPEAKING LANGUAGES: Portuguese (C2) | English (C2) | Spanish (B1)

PROJECTS

Construction Business Web Application

TypeScript, React.js, Tailwind CSS, Cloudinary - Current

Developed a responsive website and am currently implementing an estimate calculator and invoice generator, which can increase in **80%** stakeholders' productivity and streamlined customer acquisition.

Clothing E-Commerce Platform

JavaScript, MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js - Current

Developed a scalable e-commerce platform featuring secure user authentication, an admin panel, a shopping cart, and payment integration. Which improve user experience by **70%** and operational efficiency by **60%**.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Independent Consultant - Toronto, Canada | May 2024 - Present

- Designed and implemented **20+** end-to-end web applications ensuring seamless interaction between **front- end** and **back-end** systems.
- Contributed to **open source** projects on GitHub by developing features, fixing bugs, and improving documentation.
- Debugged, enhanced and maintained applications, driving continuous improvements and delivering an exceptional **user experience** across the development lifecycle.

Creative Director & Digital Strategist

Independent Consultant - Texas, United States | 2016 - 2024

- Implemented data-driven strategies driving a 20% improvement in client conversion rates.
- Collaborated with over 168 teams over 8 years to execute omni-channel marketing initiatives.
- Maintained 8-17% repeat business rate over 8 years, demonstrating strong client satisfaction.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATES

Front-End Development | FreeCodeCamp - USA | 2024

Bachelor of Science | Pontifícia Universidade Católica - MG/Brazil | 2012 - 2014

Major: Mechanical Engineering